New England and Clifton Copper Company of Arizona records, 1900-1913
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
New England and Clifton Copper Company of Arizona records, 1900-1913
AZ 285
New England and Clifton Copper Company of Arizona
This collection includes correspondence, legal papers, financial and production records, ore shipments, assay records, and lists of stockholders relate to New England and Clifton Copper Company operations in Greenlee County, Ariz. Some legal papers and correspondence are available for the two earlier companies. Bulk of collection is personal and business correspondence of Edmund Bristol.
3.3 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
The New England and Clifton Copper Company of Arizona was formed in 1903 from the New England Copper Company and the Clifton Consolidated Copper Mines of Arizona. Edmund Bristol was the Vice President and Managing Director of the company.
Organization
This collection is organized into three series:
Series I: Official Papers, 1901-1909
Series II: Correspondence, 1900-1913
Series III: Financial and Production Records, 1903-1909
Scope and Content Note
This collection includes correspondence, legal papers, financial and production records, ore shipments, assay records, and lists of stockholders relate to New England and Clifton Copper Company operations in Greenlee County, Ariz. Some legal papers and correspondence are available for the two earlier companies. Bulk of collection is personal and business correspondence of Edmund Bristol.
Access Terms
Bristol, Edmund
New England and Clifton Copper Company of Arizona -- Archives
New England Copper Company
Clifton Consolidated Copper Mines of Arizona
Copper mines and mining -- Arizona -- History -- Sources
Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Greenlee County -- History -- Sources
Mineral industries -- Arizona -- Finance -- Sources
Correspondence
Blueprints
Container List
- Series I: Official Papers, 1901-1909
  - New England and Clifton Copper Company of Arizona Charter and By-laws (2 copies). 1907 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - New England and Clifton Copper Company of Arizona reports. 1904-1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - New England Copper Company reports. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clifton Consolidated Copper Mines of Arizona, Ltd. prospectus and reports. 1901-1902 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clifton Consolidated Copper Mines of Arizona, Ltd. notorial certificates for various documents. 1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of meetings. 1901-1909 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Legal papers, indentures and agreements. 1901-1909 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Legal papers, court cases. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Lists of stockholders. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous papers. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Maps and blueprints. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - San Francisco River Railroad Company. 1907 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous printed material. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1900-1913
  - Correspondence: General and miscellaneous. 1902-1910 (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
  - Correspondence: Armstrong, Henry F. (N. E. & C. C. Co.). July 1910-December 1910 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Blaire T. (Stockholder, London). 1907 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Boesse, Quincy Ward (Attorney, New York). 1907 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Demme, Rodney A. (Banker, Switzerland). 1903-1909 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Correspondence: Detroit Copper Mining Company. 1909 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Dunham, L. A. (Stockholder). 1900-1907 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Field & Fay (Stockholders, Boston). 1907-1908 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Forbes, D. L. H. (Assistant General Manager, N. E. & C. C. Co.). 1907-1908 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Hammond, L. P. (Denver Engineering Works). 1908-1909 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Hampton, John R. (Attorney, Clifton, Arizona). 1904-1909 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Hoyt, Alfred W. (Stockholder). 1906-1909 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: King, Jacob (Manager, N. E. & C. C. Co.). 1906 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: McDaniel, A. K. (Superintendent, N. E. & C. C. Co.). May 1909-October 1909 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Mason, F. W. & Co. (Brokers, Boston). 1906-1907 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Morse, E. Rollins (Banker & Broker, New York; Stockholder; President, N. E. & C. C. Co.). 1903-1909 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Moses, Horace (Foreman, Antietam Mine; Superintendent, N. E. & C. C. Co.). 1908 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Murphy, Annie (Secretary to Edmund Bristol). 1907, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Perry, F. H. (Superintendent, N.. E. & C. C. Co.). September 1907-June 1909 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence: Solsbury, George (French Agent, Paris). 1906-1909 (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
  - Correspondence: Steele, James S. (Gloucester, Massachusetts). 1907-1909 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Stirling, A. W. (Solicitor, London). 1903-1904 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Veitch, Alex (General Manager, N. E. & C. C. Co.). May 1906-May 1908 (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence: Wambaugh, Eugene (Stockholder). 1906-1909 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence: Wiard, Edward (Consulting Engineer, N. E. & C. C. Co.). 1908-1909 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Phippen, C. E. (Secretary/Treasurer, N. E. & C. C. Co.). 1906-1909 (Box 6, Folder 1-10)
  - Correspondence: Armour, Eric N. (Toronto, Canada). 1903-1909 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Ayling Arthur (President, New England Copper Co of Arizona; Manager, N. E. & C. C. Co.). 1903-1906 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Elliott, Alexander E. (Stockholder). 1906-1909 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Fischer, Charles (Secretary, Clifton Consolidated Copper Mines of Arizona, Ltd.). 1902-1904 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: McNamara, W. S. (Cashier, N. E. & C. C. Co.). September 1906-November 1908 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence: Potter, Dell M. (President and Treasurer, Clifton Northern Railroad Co.). 1906-1909 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Raymond, Robert L. (Counselor-at-Law, Boston). 1906-1907 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Shannon Copper Company (Amster, N. L., President and Bennie, J. W., Manager). 1907-1909 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Swift, Lindsay (President, N. E. & C. C. Co.). 1904-1908 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Wells, George W. (Stockholder). 1906-1909 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Westengard, Jens I. (Counselor-at-Law, Boston). 1903 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Wyman, Alphonso A. (Counselor-at-Law, Boston). 1903-1910 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Various distilleries. 1911-1913 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Bristol, Edmund, personal (Vice-president, N. E. & C. C. Co.). 1908-1910 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, etc.: Rampo Iron Works, New York. 1902-1904 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Smith, William H. (N. E. & C. C. Co.). February 1909-May 1909 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Series III: Financial and Production Records, 1903-1909
  - Daily Labor Reports (from William H. Smith and others). February 1909-November 1909 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Ore Shipments, smelter statements, assay records, custom statements. 1906-1909 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Daily Ore Shipments. 1907-1909 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Production and Development Records. 1907-1909 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Summary of Expenses, mining cost statements. September 1906-August 1909 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous financial records. 1903-1909 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous bills. 1903-1909 (Box 8, Folder 11)